Processing d:\man\man\sample_question_bank.pdf...

--- RAW TEXT START ---
QUESTION BANK
Course Code: CY25CO1 Course Name: APPLIED CHEMISTRY û I Class: I (Common to all)
UNIT I û WATER TECHNOLOGY
Water quality parameters and standards. Industrial feed water, Remediation. Municipal water treatment. Desalination.
Knowledge
Q.No Questions
Level
PART- A (2 marks)
Write the significance of colour in water.
1. K2
State term of taste and odour of water.
2. K2
3. How can hardness of water be detected? K2
Mention the significance of feed water.
4. K2
Write term of hardness of water.
5. K2
Distinguish between carbonate and non-carbonate hardness.
6. K2
State term of hard water and soft water.
7. K2
Mention the units of hardness. How hardness is expressed in terms of CaCO
3
8. equivalent? K3
Write down the causes for alkalinity of water.
9. K2
Any two disinfection methods for municipal water treatment.
10. K2
State term of break point of chlorination
11. K2
12. Write the reasons for caustic embrittlement in boilers. K2
PART- B (16 marks)
1. What are the water quality parameters? Explain their significance. K2
Write the detailed description about the municipal water treatment process.
2. K2
Explain the treatments involved in boiler feed water by the important internal
3. conditioning aspects. K2
With necessary diagram, describe the reverse osmosis method for the desalination
4. K3
of brackish water.
5. Explain the industrial feed water with suitable examples. K2
How is water softened by ion exchange method? Explain in detail with a neat
6. K2
diagram.
Describe the principle and procedure involved in the zeolite process for water
7. K2
treatment.
Signature of the staff Signature of the HoD
QUESTION BANK
Department of Computer Science and Engineering
Course Code: CY25CO1 Course Name: APPLIED CHEMISTRY û I Class: I CSE
UNIT II û NANOCHEMISTRY
Classification, Size dependent properties. Preparation of nanomaterials, Top-down and Botton - Up approaches,
Applications.
Knowledge
Q.No Questions
Level
PART- A (2 marks)
List out the uses of nanoparticles and nanorods.
1. K2
Mention the applications of nano cluster and nano wires.
2. K2
Why nanomaterials are size dependent?
3. K2
Write any properties of nanomaterials with a suitable example.
4. K2
State term of nanoparticles. Give any two examples.
5. K2
List out the application of nanoclusters.
6. K2
Give the important application and properties of nanoclusters
7. K2
Mention any four applications of nanorods and nano wires.
8. K2
Differentiate electro deposition and electro spinning.
9. K2
List out the types of carbon nanotubes.
10. K2
Write about the important categories of nanomaterials
11. K2
PART- B (16 marks)
1. Explain the size-dependent properties of nanomaterials. K2
Discuss the types of carbon nanotubes and their applications.
2. K2
Discuss in a detailed manner about the properties and uses of nanoclusters and
3. nanowires. K2
4. With a neat sketch, explain sol-gel synthesis for producing nano materials. K3
Explain the preparation of nanomaterials by electro deposition and Chemical vapour
5. deposition. K2
Explain the applications of nanomaterials in medicine, agriculture, energy and
6. K2
catalysis with examples.
Signature of the staff Signature of the HoD
QUESTION BANK
Department of Computer Science and Engineering
Course Code: CY25CO1 Course Name: APPLIED CHEMISTRY û I Class: I CSE
UNIT III û ELECTRO û CHEMISTRY
Electrochemical cell, Electrode potential, Redox reaction. Conductivity of electrolytes, Factors.
Knowledge
Q.No Questions
Level
PART- A (2 marks)
State term of cell and conductivity.
1. K2
Give the examples of anode and cathode cells.
2. K2
Mention the uses of electrochemical cell.
3. K2
List out the functions of salt bridge in an electrochemical cell.
4. K2
Write the term of standard electrode potential.
5. K2
Mention the uses of redox reaction.
6. K2
How is standard hydrogen electrode (SHE) used as a reference electrode?
7. K2
Differentiate between oxidation potential and reduction potential with examples.
8. K2
Differentiate electro deposition and electro spinning.
9. K2
Give two examples from electrochemical processes.
10. K2
Write term of conductivity, molar conductivity, and equivalent conductivity.
11. K2
List the factors affecting conductivity of electrolytes.
12. K2
PART- B (16 marks)
1. With a neat diagram, explain the construction and working of a Daniell cell. K3
Write the Nernst equation for electrode potential and explain the terms involved.
2. K2
Discuss the factors that affect electrode potential.
3. K2
Explain how electron transfer occurs in a galvanic cell through redox reactions.
4. K2
With a neat diagram, explain the measurement of specific and equivalent conductance.
5. K3
Explain with neat diagram, measurement of emf of a cell with significances.
6. K2
Signature of the staff Signature of the HoD
QUESTION BANK
Department of Computer Science and Engineering
Course Code: CY25CO1 Course Name: APPLIED CHEMISTRY û I Class: I CSE
UNIT IV û CORROSION AND CONTROL
Chemical and electrochemical corrosions, galvanic series,
--- RAW TEXT END ---

Extracted 88 questions.
1. [PART- A] ù: Write the significance of colour in water.... (NoneM, K1)
2. [PART- A] 1.: State term of taste and odour of water.... (NoneM, K2)
3. [PART- A] 3.: How can hardness of water be detected? Mention the significance of feed water.... (NoneM, K2)
4. [PART- A] 4.: Write term of hardness of water.... (NoneM, K2)
5. [PART- A] 5.: Distinguish between carbonate and non-carbonate hardness.... (NoneM, K2)
6. [PART- A] 6.: State term of hard water and soft water.... (NoneM, K2)
7. [PART- A] 7.: Mention the units of hardness. How hardness is expressed in terms of CaCO... (NoneM, K2)
8. [PART- A] 8.: equivalent? Write down the causes for alkalinity of water.... (NoneM, K3)
9. [PART- A] 9.: Any two disinfection methods for municipal water treatment.... (NoneM, K2)
10. [PART- A] 10.: State term of break point of chlorination... (NoneM, K2)
